CURRICULUM VITAE OF WILLEM HENDRIK THYSSE

PROFILE

I am an experienced security contractor with international experience in the commercial and government sectors. I have extensive PSD training and experience, gaining my practical skills from serving 4 years within the VIP guard unit of the South African Police Service as well as working as a security operative in Afghanistan for 4 years. Highlights include the guarding of late President Nelson Mandela, President Thabo Mbeki, Minister Pik Botha and Minister Roelf Meyer.

I have also managerial, logistical and organisational experience as an Explosive Detection dog handler as well as Narcotic Detection dog handler.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

CONTACT DETAILS

Postal address: PO Box 182

OUDTSHOORN

6620

South- Africa

Telephone nr: 0027 84 523 5884 Alternative nr: 0027 72 523 5884

E-mail: williethysse@yahoo.com

PERSONAL DATA

Surname: Thysse First name: Willem H

I D nr: 730617 5090 08 7

Passport nr: A04480060 (Exp. 11/12/2024)

Any Visas Have a valid USA Visa (Exp. 05/10/2020)

Age: 40

Nationality: South- African
Marital status: Married
Dependants: Wife & child
Health: Very good

Language proficiency: Afrikaans and English

Driver's license: Yes

Available: Immediately

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

♦ AMK-9 Detection Services, Afghanistan (Nov. 2010 – Jan. 2013)

Key Responsibilities:

- Explosive and narcotic patrol dog-handler and trainer.
- Kennel master at some of the FOBS.
- Certified by the US Army instructors in Texas, USA.
- Searching of vehicles, personnel, luggage, parcels, buildings and open areas by means of the K-9's.
- Maintain K9 training and training records.
- Recognize K9 diseases, familiar with hygiene requirements, and know the physical condition of the K-9.
- Awarded "Top Dog Achievement" in April 2012

◆ JSI (Janus Security), Afghanistan (2009 – 2010)

Key Responsibilities:

 Safe, secure transport for cash, power generation equipment, remote countryside / high-density urban areas, and construction equipment and materials

◆ SAPS Dog-Unit Oudtshoorn (2004 – 2008)

Key Responsibilities:

- Investigating high profile cases and catching criminals
- Securing safety of specific places by using explosive dogs.
- Search for narcotics by using narcotic dogs.

♦ SAPS Plettenberg Bay (1996 – 2004)

Key Responsibilities:

- Visible Policing in town (shift work) attending to normal day to day complaints
- Managing the control room and attending to public's complaints
- Shift commander leading the team
- Crime Prevention Unit: to prevent crime before it happens, to identify problem points, know your criminals, planning of operations to prevent crime.
- Garden Route Crime Prevention Unit as above but in the whole Garden Route Area
- Special House-breaking Task Force attending to only housebreaking cases in town and surrounding Garden Route Area and arresting of high profile criminals

◆ Special VIP Guard Unit, Pretoria (1993 – 1996)

Key Responsibilities:

- Provide static protection to designated persons
- Provide close protection to designated persons whilst in transit
- Provide pedestrian escort to designated persons within a close protection environment
- Compile a threat and risk assessments for a close protection operation

SUMMARY OF COURSES COMPLETED

Basic SAPS training course

Street survival & crowd control course

VIP basic protection course VIP advanced protection course Human rights & policing course

CRIM system course Advanced driving course

Crime prevention module 1 course Crime prevention module 2 course

Patrol Explosive-Detection dog-handler course (SAPS)
Patrol Narcotic-Detection dog-handler course (SAPS)

General driving and maintenance Street survival & use of firearm course

PSD & Close Protection course

First aid level 3 course

Special events security officer course

Security Manager Course

Patrol Narcotic-Detection course (Hill Country Dog Centre, Texas, USA) Patrol Explosive-Detection course (Hill Country Dog Centre, Texas, USA)

FPOS medical course

EDUCATIONAL AND TRAINING QUALIFICATIONS

Secondary Education

Institution: Oudtshoorn Tech High

Course: Grade 12

Subjects: Languages (Afrikaans & English)

Maths Science Biology

Spray-painting Motor body works

Year: 1992

Qualification: Senior Certificate

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I am very fond of nature and the great outdoors. My greatest relaxation is going to the beach for some rock and surf fishing.

In my spare time I enjoy cooking and spending quality time with my family. I also participate in pigeon racing.

References are available on request

Certificates and documents are available on request.